let's look at the solution to our MSI
quiz Redux results in the same behavior
as in the previous quiz both of them
have the state as I and then when readex
occurs in C ones cache it sends out the
read request gets the block from memory
and now it has the Block in the shared
state c2 still has the Block in the
invalid state
now when c2 writes to X it sends out a
write miss request it will get the data
and then write to its cache so it gets
the block now in the modified state c1
meanwhile transitions from the shared
state to the invalid state because it
observes the write requests sent by c2
and then when C one wants to write it
does pretty much the same thing as c2
just did it puts a write miss request on
the bus gets the block rights to it puts
it in the modified State
meanwhile c2 has to intervene and
provide the data that c1 gets and then
because we snoop the right we need to
transition to an invalid state note that
if a block is in M state in any cache
all the other caches have to have that
block in the invalid state if a cache
has a block in a shared state all the
other caches need to have the Block in
either the shared or the invalid caches
so pretty much we can have one has M or
others have I or we have several can
have s and the rest have I we cannot
have m and s in the system at the same
time for the same block and definitely
we cannot have mmm